Your lighter is...
你的打火机是...
Ronson diesel lighter.
朗森柴油打火机。
Made in America.
美国制造。
How are you, friend?
朋友你好吗？
Two!
二！
Don't look there.
别看那儿。
They are connected.
它们是相连的。
Chief.
首席。
We can't hear what they say here.
我们在这里听不到他们说什么。
What if it was closer?
如果再近一点呢？
No need to listen to what they say.
没必要听他们说什么。
We must not act rashly.
我们切不可轻举妄动。
After they separated,
他们分开后，
we will also separate.
我们也会分开。
You and A-Chuan...
你和阿川……
With Tian.
与田.
Me and Xiao Lai Zi,
Me and Xiao Lai Zi,
and people who work together,
以及一起工作的人们，
understand.
理解。
Go away.
离开。
Good.
好的。
Border regional government
边境地区政府
after stopping the circulation of French money
法国货币停止流通后
and replace it with fringe money.
并用额外的钱来代替它。
The border area's financial work has reversed the situation
边境地区金融工作扭转局面
social stability in border areas
边境地区社会稳定
and community life
和社区生活
has also improved a lot.
也进步了很多。
It's just that I didn't expect it
只是我没想到而已
in the marginal money design and printing team
在边际货币设计和印刷团队中
in the money design and printing team.
在钱币设计和印刷团队中。
These two spies
这两个间谍
is there a person named wild goose?
有一个叫大雁的人吗？
Correct.
正确的。
There is one more.
还有一个。
Codenamed Xi Que.
代号西阙。
Xi Que?
Xi Que?
My Special Case Team colleagues and I
我和我的特案团队同事
I've been investigating them for so long,
我研究他们很久了
unexpectedly before being arrested, they leaked information,
没想到在被捕前，他们泄露了信息，
they ran away
他们逃跑了
also took away two coins
还拿走了两枚硬币
and a formula for printing money
以及印钞的公式
we tracked it all the way.
我们一路追踪。
Found traces of them in Jinan.
在济南发现了他们的踪迹。
Unexpectedly, just shot
没想到刚一拍
they are blurred again.
他们再次变得模糊。
I chased Xi Que
我追过西阙
arrived in Shanghai
抵达上海
This is a magpie.
这是一只喜鹊。
And also the data
还有数据
did you manage to catch it?
你抓住它了吗？
a little more.
再来一点。
He remains vague.
他仍然含糊其辞。
I'm hurt too.
我也受伤了
Can only blame myself for being useless.
只能怪自己没用。
You can find spies,
你可以找到间谍，
it's not easy anymore.
这不再容易了。
The situation is urgent.
情况紧急。
I don't understand Shanghai either.
我也不懂上海。
So just can use
所以就可以使用
emergency contact procedures
紧急联络程序
previously,
之前，
I hope you get your help
我希望你能得到你的帮助
I'll be right away
我马上就来
gathered several colleagues in charge of the intelligence station,
召集了情报站的几位负责同事，
to discuss this together.
一起讨论这个问题。
The magpie's left hand and stomach had been shot.
喜鹊的左手和腹部都被击中。
I think he must be hiding somewhere to treat his wounds.
我想他一定是躲在某个地方治疗伤口。
What are your plans after this?
这之后你有什么计划？
Wait until my wound heals,
等我的伤口痊愈
I want to join your action.
我想加入你们的行动。
Don't worry, treat your wounds first.
别着急，先处理一下伤口。
Come on, follow him.
来吧，跟着他。
Mother, I want to eat Tanghulu.
妈妈，我想吃糖葫芦。
Good.
好的。
How much does one Tang Hu Lu cost?
糖葫芦多少钱一盒？
Not selling, not selling.
不卖，不卖。
I want to eat.
我想吃。
Step aside.
退到一边去。
What is it?
它是什么？
If you don't want to sell, don't sell.
如果你不想卖，就不要卖。
I told you not to sell.
我告诉过你不要卖。
Why do you hit a child?
你为什么打孩子？
Small child, very small.
小孩子，很小。
Why do you have the heart to hit him?
为什么你还忍心打他？
Why do you hit a child?
你为什么打孩子？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Chase him.
追他。
Pay as needed.
根据需要付费。
You're crazy, aren't you?
你疯了，不是吗？
not good.
不好。
The old road has been discovered.
旧路被发现了。
Do not move.
不要动。
This dragon stone table is made of fine clay.
此龙石桌是用细粘土制成的。
It could be said that mud is stronger than stone.
可以说泥比石坚。
You must not be using it properly
你一定没有正确使用它
can only make this crack.
只能做出这个裂缝。
No. I mean road boss.
不，我是说路老板。
I use it for sharpening and writing
我用它来锐化和书写
not be a board cutter.
不是一名切板工。
How could it not be used properly?
怎么会不能正常使用呢？
Moreover
而且
your maintenance costs
您的维护成本
a bit too expensive.
有点太贵了。
To repair this crack
为了修复这个裂缝
I used stone powder to turn it into glue.
我用石粉把它变成了胶水。
For sharpening and lubricating.
用于锐化和润滑。
Then use yellow wax and ink on it
然后在上面涂上黄蜡和墨水
to color.
填色。
Look,
看，
intact as before.
完好如初。
Can you still see the crack?
你还能看到裂缝吗？
Invisible.
无形的。
But, Boss Lu,
但是，陆总，
At first, what you did to me... was interesting.
起初，你对我做的事……很有趣。
What's with the sound?
声音怎么了？
cut off without holes
切断无孔
but I made it crack after using it a few times.
但我用了几次后就裂了。
Don't be afraid to sell fake goods.
不要害怕出售假货。
No, how do you talk?
不，你怎么说话？
Tuan Lu,
Tuan Lu,
I've looked after your business many times.
我已经多次照顾过你的生意了。
If you sell me fake goods again,
如果你再卖给我假货
That's too unkind.
这也太不厚道了吧。
You two
你们俩
do you want me to do business?
你想让我做生意吗？
The old way
老办法
application submitted to the organization
向组织提交的申请
Is there any reply from the organization?
有组织回复吗？
Saying this inkstone is fake.
说这砚台是假的。
Do not be angry
别生气
quickly tell me
快告诉我
your request
你的申请
approved by the organization.
经组织批准。
You can keep lurking.
你可以继续潜伏。
A little plan.
一个小计划。
Don't break it
不要打破它
I've spent a lot of money to fix it.
我花了很多钱来修复它。
Then got the left twin
然后得到了左边的双胞胎
What is the organization saying?
该组织在说什么？
No, what are you doing?
不，你在做什么？
Quickly tell me.
快告诉我吧。
The purpose of the organization is
该组织的宗旨是
you should be more careful.
你应该更加小心。
You can do experiments in peace,
可以安心做实验，
observe the reaction.
观察反应。
Don't rush to success
不要急于成功
don't let him know your intentions.
不要让他知道你的意图。
Understand.
理解。
There is still one important thing
还有一件事很重要
organization.
组织。
Asking you to control the husband and wife relationship.
要求你把控夫妻关系。
Distance and boundaries
距离和边界
don't go too far
别走得太远
Also don't get too close.
也不要靠得太近。
Far will be suspicious,
远了就会被怀疑，
close would be dangerous.
靠近就会有危险。
You must remember these eight words.
这八个字你一定要记住。
I will remember it.
我会记住它。
Both of us
我们俩
it's been noisy lately
最近很吵
I happen to be able to take advantage of this opportunity
我正好可以利用这个机会
stubbornness
固执
I understand.
我明白。
Oh yes
哦是的
let me show you something.
让我给你看一些东西。
What is this?
这是什么？
The document you recorded
您记录的文档
recorded a large number of acts of betrayal by the Chongqing government.
记录了重庆政府大量的背叛行为。
As if preparing to receive...
仿佛正准备接收……
Japan's proposal to sign a defense treaty.
日本提议签署防卫条约。
Accepting the placement of Japanese troops on Chinese soil.
接受日本军队在中国领土上的部署。
Even recognizing the fake Manchurian state, reorganizing the Chinese government.
甚至承认假满洲国，重组中国政府。
After publication,
发表后，
Domestic and international public opinion was in an uproar.
国内外舆论哗然。
Unanimously condemned Chiang Kai-shek's treasonous policies.
一致谴责蒋介石的叛国政策。
old road,
老路，
can you give me this newspaper?
你能给我这份报纸吗？
I'm useful.
我很有用。
OK, just keep it.
好吧，就保留它吧。
Correct.
正确的。
There's one more thing,
还有一件事，
I feel like I should tell you.
我觉得我应该告诉你。
Today I met a colleague
今天我认识了一位同事
met, he told me,
遇见了，他告诉我，
there are two military spies hiding in Yan'an,
延安藏有两名军事间谍，
steal coins there
在那里偷硬币
and printing paper.
和打印纸。
Zhu Yuhua also told me,
Zhu Yuhua also told me,
said that Shan's plan also planned to counterfeit foreign currency.
说单的计划还计划伪造外币。
What do you think of these two special agents
对于这两位特工，你怎么看？
is it related to the Shan Project?
与掸邦计划有关吗？
Still not sure.
还是不确定。
Tomorrow morning
明天早上
I will meet with several people in charge of intelligence posts
我会见几个负责情报岗位的人
to meet at the Hai Zhong Xian Tea House to discuss this.
约在海中仙茶馆见面商议此事。
Tomorrow you have to pay attention
明天你要注意
business movements and military bases.
商业活动和军事基地。
Do a good job of peripheral security.
做好周边安全工作。
Good.
好的。
There's one more thing.
还有一件事。
Don't smoke anymore
别再抽烟了
Your eyes are quite sharp too.
你的眼睛也很锐利。
This
这
friend from Yan'an today.
今天是延安的朋友。
Kak Tian!
卡克田！
Kak Tian.
嘉田.
What is your assignment to Shanghai?
您到上海的任务是什么？
Apart from people who
除了那些人
the person who contacted you,
与您联系的人，
is there anyone else?
还有其他人吗？
Mine.
矿。
My job
我的工作
What's that?
那是什么？
This is a war against Japan to save the country.
这是一场抗日救国的战争。
Mine.
矿。
Contact?
接触？
Is Chinese
是中国人吗
I know you can't say anything
我知道你什么也不能说
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
We've followed
我们已经关注了
your previous contact.
您之前的联系方式。
Following the roots of this plant
追随这种植物的根部
will get a lot of information.
会得到很多信息。
Now it's you or not,
现在无论是不是你，
Up to you.
由你决定。
You
你
won't work
行不通
you just see
你只是看到
salah.
萨拉赫。
You didn't see either.
你也没有看到。
I'm about to die
我快要死了
still loud-mouthed
仍然大声说话
today just throw him here
今天就把他扔到这里
tomorrow call 2 swords to clean up the body.
明天召唤2把剑来清理尸体。
Good
好的
I have a request.
我有一个请求。
Say it.
说吧。
I want to smoke.
我想要吸烟。
No need.
不需要。
It's in my pocket
它在我的口袋里
or smoke from the hometown.
或来自故乡的烟。
Fragrant
香
I really don't understand these CCP people
我实在不理解这些共产党人
You're already dying, still haven't smoked a good cigarette.
你已经快死了，还没抽过好烟。
I can
我可以
already home?
已经到家了吗？
Tuan Shan Xia.
Tuan Shan Xia.
Owned by Han Lu.
属于韩露。
How is your health condition?
您的健康状况如何？
It's much better.
好多了。
Thank You.
谢谢。
I know you have experienced suffering
我知道你经历过痛苦
never bothered you
从来没有打扰过你
today after finding out you came home from the hospital,
今天得知你出院回家后
I specially came to celebrate.
我特地来庆祝。
That's right, Miss Han Lu.
没错，韩露小姐。
Tuan Shan Xia.
Tuan Shan Xia.
I also prepared special champagne for you.
我还为你准备了特别的香槟。
Thank you for Mr. Shan Xia's kindness.
谢谢山霞先生的好意。
However, recently,
然而，最近，
I want to be alone.
我想单独待一会儿。
For Han Lu,
对于韩璐来说，
I have also experienced death.
我也经历过死亡。
Death is what made me start a new life.
死亡让我开始了新的生活。
I hope...
我希望...
Miss Han Lu can also welcome a new birth.
韩露小姐也能迎来新生了。
It is clear,
很明显，
pkc that cooperates with Tian,
与Tian合作的pkc，
bernama Lu Yousheng.
bernama Lu Yousheng.
People who know him call him old road.
认识他的人都称他为老路。
He owns a shop called Yumo
他拥有一家名为Yumomo的商店
the shop owner is named Yumo
店主名叫雨沫
Yumo Painting and Calligraphy shop
玉墨书画店
we still have greater achievements.
我们还有更大的成就。
Today as we hunker down
今天当我们蹲下来时
around the bookstore
书店周围
Section Chief Chen also happened to come
陈科长也正好来了
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
what did he go for
他去做什么
seems to be repairing an inkstone
好像是在修砚台
inkstone
inkstone
we asked the people around the calligraphy and painting shop again.
我们又询问了字画店周围的人。
Department Head Chen was a regular customer of the shop
陈部门长是该店的常客
come often?
经常来吗？
No wonder when you're in Waitan,
难怪当你在外滩时，
I feel very familiar with the old road
感觉老路很熟悉
he must have appeared near our shop
他肯定出现在我们店附近
team leader
队长
it seems your previous suspicions were correct.
看来你之前的怀疑是正确的。
Chen Jia Ping
Chen Jia Ping
who is hiding behind this CCP.
到底是谁躲在这个CCP的背后。
This time it's for sure
这次是肯定的
kalau Chen Jia Ping bilang
kalau Chen Jia Ping bilang
he went to the old shop
他去了老店
just to buy brushes, ink, paper and inkwells.
只是为了买画笔、墨水、纸张和墨水瓶。
Not knowing Lao Lu's true identity.
不知道老鲁的真实身份。
How about this?
这个怎么样？
Then arrest Lao Lu
然后抓捕老鲁
forcing him to identify Chen Jiaping
逼他认出陈家平
facing the Communist Party
面对共产党
This trick of yours won't work
你的这个伎俩是行不通的
should be patient
应该有耐心
fishing for small fish with shrimp
钓小鱼和虾
catch small fish, catch big fish
钓小鱼，钓大鱼
I introspect the mistakes I made,
我反省自己所犯的错误
for being too impatient,
因为太不耐烦，
after that, stay tuned.
之后，请继续关注。
Keep watching.
一直在看。
Must be very careful.
一定要非常小心。
Be patient in everything
凡事要有耐心
strong heart
坚强的心
The iron dagger was sharpened into a needle.
铁匕首被磨成了针。
Are you awake?
你醒着么？
Why are you like that to me?
你为什么要这样对我？
Owned by Han Lu.
属于韩露。
Don't be angry.
别生气。
You are so outrageous!
你太离谱了！
Why are you like that to me?
你为什么要这样对我？
I'm sincere with you.
我对你是真诚的。
Absolutely no lies.
绝对没有谎言。
I can swear
我可以发誓
You think you do this
你认为你这样做
can I accept you?
我可以接受你吗？
For Han Lu,
对于韩璐来说，
I hope today...
我希望今天...
Is the beginning of
是开始
new life.
新生活。
New life?
新生活？
You insult me
你侮辱了我
but instead talked about a new life.
而是谈论了新的生活。
Owned by Han Lu.
属于韩露。
Look at it.
看它。
This is a gift I specially prepared for you.
这是我专门为你准备的礼物。
A cinema especially for you.
专门为您打造的电影院。
After it finishes,
完成后，
will premiere here.
将在这里首映。
And this cinema
还有这个电影院
can only be played over and over again.
只能一遍又一遍地播放。
All the films you starred in
你主演的所有电影
because I know,
因为我知道，
you like movies
你喜欢电影
movies are your life
电影就是你的生活
is everything to you
就是你的一切
and I
和我
I don't expect to have all of yours.
我不指望拥有你的全部。
I just hope
我只是希望
behind you
在你身后
secretly helping you achieve your dreams
秘密地帮助你实现你的梦想
This...
这...
It's my love for you.
这是我对你的爱。
Liuli Guoguo.
Liuli Guoguo.
This is pretty good too.
这也挺好的。
I like this color.
我喜欢这个颜色。
Get out.
出去。
Go, go.
走吧，走吧。
What is this?
这是什么？
Nona Hong Ling.
诺娜·洪凌.
It's been three days.
已经三天了。
Gambling debt last month,
上个月的赌博债务，
last month?
上个月？
Give me two more days.
再给我两天时间。
I'll be getting paid soon.
我很快就会收到工资。
Salary?
薪水？
How many hours can you jump a day?
一天可以跳几个小时？
Your salary
你的工资
minus the boss's bookkeeping.
减去老板的簿记。
How much do you have left?
你还剩多少钱？
There are several guests
有好几个客人
who owes me a tip.
谁欠我小费。
You still have tips.
你还是有窍门的。
The spare bench soon disappeared.
空出来的长凳很快就消失了。
Xiang... Trust me.
翔……相信我。
I will definitely...
我一定会...
Give me a few more days
再给我几天时间
I... I definitely...
我……我绝对……
I...
我...
I'll give you three more days.
我再给你三天时间。
If it is still not paid,
如果还没付款的话
I sold you to the fireworks room.
我把你卖到烟花房了
It is clear?
很明显？
Road.
路。
Only three days.
只有三天。
Nona.
诺娜。
Is he new?
他是新人吗？
Can not?
不能？
Invites you to dance
邀请你跳舞
I can only do the simplest.
我只能做最简单的。
A little plan.
一个小计划。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
I teach you.
我教你。
Isn't this Mr. Yao?
这不是姚先生吗？
Long time no see.
好久不见。
Want to dance?
要跳舞？
I'll accompany you to dance, okay?
我陪你跳舞好不好？
go away
离开
Good.
好的。
It's been a long time since I came.
我来已经很久了。
Nona,
诺娜，
Want to dance to earn money.
想跳舞赚钱。
What is it?
它是什么？
You come from the village, right?
你是村里来的吧？
Presuming here is the market?
假设这里是市场？
Just opening one stall can do business.
只要开一个摊位就可以做生意。
I come from the village, why?
我来自农村，为什么？
You bully people.
你欺负人。
I still have to sell here
我还得在这里卖
Where are you from?
你从哪来？
Don't you know the rules?
你不知道规则吗？
Get out.
出去。
I don't want to go out
我不想出去
why asked me out?
为什么约我出去？
You're still stubborn.
你还是很固执。
Want to die.
想死。
It is okay, right?
没关系，对吧？
Is it hurt?
受伤了吗？
I'm about to die, I'm about to die.
我快要死了，我快要死了。
Why are you still stunned?
为什么你还愣住了？
Drag this damn girl out!
把这个该死的女人拖出去！
go away
离开
Don't touch me, I can walk alone
别碰我，我可以一个人走
what place is this? Bullying people!
这是什么地方？欺负人！
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Did you dirty your clothes?
你弄脏你的衣服了吗？
You are
你是
how much does it cost?
它要多少钱？
I will compensate you.
我会补偿你的。
Compensation?
赔偿？
Are you able to compensate?
你能补偿吗？
I have money.
我有钱。
This cheongsam of mine was ordered by Hong Fuji.
我的这件旗袍是洪富士订购的。
From real silk,
由真丝制成，
50 Yuan more.
多了50元。
Can't be washed either.
也不能洗。
Like this, it's done.
就这样，就完成了。
You see.
你看。
Really rich.
真是有钱啊。
Sixty.
六十。
Nona,
诺娜，
why do you carry so much money?
你为什么带这么多钱？
Always unsafe.
总是不安全。
I live there
我住在那里
above and below there are dozens of houses.
上下都有数十间房屋。
There is a big bakery seller.
有一个大面包店卖家。
As a messenger,
作为一个使者，
a fortune teller with a bald head
光头算命师
there are people of all kinds.
有各种各样的人。
Looks like there are still two pickpockets.
看来还有两个扒手。
Then put this money at home,
然后把这些钱放在家里，
not dare.
不敢。
So can only carry it.
所以只能扛着。
Why do you want to be a female dancer?
你为什么想成为一名女舞者？
Also don't understand anything.
也什么都不懂。
I see your makeup...
我看到你的妆...
Unlike from the village,
与村里的人不同，
Where are you from?
你从哪来？
Family from Yixing.
宜兴人家。
Why come to Shanghai?
为什么来上海？
Recently,
最近，
my father died of illness.
我的父亲因病去世了。
My mother died when I was three years old.
我三岁时母亲去世了。
I'm alone with no one to lean on
我孤身一人没有人可以依靠
since
自从
the Japanese came,
日本人来了，
I also can't do business at the shop.
我也不能在店里做生意。
I can only sell the house.
我只能卖房子。
He said he wanted to live with a distant cousin in Shanghai.
他说他想和上海的远房表弟住在一起。
But who would have thought that he had moved house.
可谁能想到，他已经搬家了。
I've been looking for him for two months, but haven't found him.
我找了他两个月了，但还没有找到。
Rent money
房租钱
eat and drink
吃和喝
You also need money, right?
你也需要钱，对吗？
Correct.
正确的。
I do have this money.
我确实有这笔钱。
Can't go on like this.
不能再这样下去了。
I saw in the movie,
我在电影里看到，
it is said that being a female dancer makes a lot of money.
据说当一名女舞者可以赚很多钱。
I just wanted to come here to try it, but unexpectedly.
本来只是想来这里尝试一下，没想到。
Here are the rules.
这是规则。
Which must be considered.
必须考虑这一点。
How do I understand, I was even encouraged
我怎么理解，还被鼓励了
by others.
由其他人。
Since childhood,
从小时候起，
I have never been treated unfairly like this.
我从来没有受到过这样的不公平对待。
So this dancer also can't be careless.
所以这个舞者也不能大意。
How old is he?
他几岁了？
Twenty.
二十。
Have good police.
有好警察。
Her face is also beautiful.
她的脸也很漂亮。
So what dance can you dance?
那么你会跳什么舞呢？
A little plan.
一个小计划。
Still have?
还有？
No more.
不再。
Only slow three
只有慢三
waltz.
华尔兹。
Blues
布鲁斯
lemur.
狐猴。
Tango.
探戈。
Exactly right
非常正确
just can't do it.
只是做不到。
It's not serious.
这并不严重。
Don't be like that, brother.
别这样，兄弟。
I see you are a good person.
我看你是个好人。
If not teach me.
如果不教我。
Teach you
教你
then I have to pay school fees
那我就得交学费
no problem, there is money.
没问题，有钱。
How much is your tuition fee?
你的学费是多少？
You really want to learn, don't you?
你真的很想学习，不是吗？
It's the same as us going to work
和我们上班一样
one hour, two Yuan.
一小时两块钱。
Two Yuan.
两元。
Good.
好的。
Not expensive.
不贵啊。
So where do you want to study?
那么你想在哪里学习？
To my house?
到我家？
But the place is small,
但地方很小，
less than five square meters.
小于五平方米。
There is also a bed and a table.
还有一张床和一张桌子。
So how do you dance?
那么你怎么跳舞呢？
Playing mahjong is not enough.
打麻将还不够。
So how?
又怎样？
Let's make it like this
让我们把它变成这样
come to my house
来我的家
But
但
I have to time it outside
我必须在外面计时
one hour five Yuan
一小时五元
more than doubled.
增加了一倍多。
You have to be clear,
你必须清楚，
aku Cai Hongling dulu di Bai Le Men
aku Cai Hongling dulu di Bai Le Men
is in Bai Le Men
位于百乐门
who queue to buy tickets
谁排队买票
already lined up to the other side of the road.
已经在路的另一边排队了。
Everyone came to support me.
大家都来支持我。
Just think about it.
考虑一下。
If you spend this money now,
如果你现在花掉这笔钱，
after you can dance the show
当你可以跳舞之后
until the time there is a commission for dance tickets
直到有舞票佣金的时候
there is a change in hourly rates.
每小时费率有变化。
The most unusual.
最不寻常的。
These are tips from customers.
这些是顾客的建议。
Putting it in your bag isn't enough either.
将其放入包中也是不够的。
Very good.
非常好。
sister,
姐姐，
today I want to study
今天我想学习
addicted man
上瘾的人
I tell you
我告诉你
I used to live in an apartment concession
我以前住在特许公寓里
at the time
当时
every month I can earn 200 Yuan more.
每个月我可以多赚200元。
Kak Hong Ling.
嘉鸿凌.
Living alone?
一个人生活？
I was so panicked this morning,
今天早上我很惊慌
I forgot to turn off the light.
我忘记关灯了。
Later we will learn here
稍后我们会在这里学习
there's new music, there's feelings
有新音乐，有感觉
phonograph
留声机
expensive isn't it?
很贵吧？
Not expensive, drizzle.
不贵，毛毛雨。
What dance do you want to learn first?
你想先学什么舞蹈？
Xiao San can do it.
小三可以的。
Then hurry up.
那就快点吧。
No problem.
没问题。
Three steps.
三步。
As the name suggests, each measure has three beats.
顾名思义，每个小节都有三个节拍。
The rhythm is strong or weak.
节奏有强有弱。
But fast tempo three
不过节奏快三
will be slower than you, San is much faster
会比你慢，San 快多了
This is the Viennese Waltz.
这就是维也纳华尔兹。
Classic fast dance
经典快舞
later I'll dance the man's step.
稍后我会跳男人的步。
You follow me.
你跟着我。
Here.
这里。
Danced almost 3 times.
跳了差不多3次。
Male and female dance partners will be closer
男女舞伴会更加亲密
start.
开始。
One two three.
一二三。
Two, two, three.
二，二，三。
When dancing almost three,
跳舞快三点的时候，
almost all the time it spins fast.
几乎所有时候它都旋转得很快。
One two three.
一二三。
Just fine?
正好？
sister,
姐姐，
maybe I'm too stupid.
也许是我太傻了。
Footsteps were too fast, I was immediately confused.
脚步声太快了，我顿时愣住了。
Maintain a rhythm, don't mess up your footsteps.
保持节奏，不要打乱脚步。
We continue.
我们继续。
Road.
路。
One two three.
一二三。
Two, two, three.
二，二，三。
Dance like this
像这样跳舞
is for your partner to control your rotation.
是让你的伙伴控制你的旋转。
So, quick three.
所以，快三。
The dance that makes men control their pleasure the most.
最让男人控制自己快感的舞蹈。
Dizzy.
晕眩的。
It's too dizzying.
太让人头晕了。
I should probably take it slow
我或许应该慢慢来
you rest for a while.
你休息一会儿。
We will practice again later.
我们稍后再练习。
Today's school fees
今天的学费
faster slower than three times more tiring.
快比慢三倍更累。
It's still at this time tomorrow.
明天还是这个时候。
I'm kind of stupid.
我有点傻。
Sis Hong Ling, you have to be more careful.
红菱姐，你要小心一点。
Don't worry, there's nothing I can't teach you.
别担心，没有什么我不能教你的。
You're so good anyway
反正你这么好
less than three months
不到三个月
can definitely become the hottest female dancer in Shanghai Tan.
绝对可以成为上海谭最炙手可热的女舞者。
Wait then
那就等一下
I will definitely not forget you.
我绝对不会忘记你。
Go ahead.
前进。
For you.
为你。
Slowly.
慢慢地。
Who is she?
她是谁？
Haven't you heard?
你没听说过吗？
Learn to dance with me.
跟我一起学跳舞吧。
Haven't I already said,
我不是已经说过了，
don't bring anyone home?
不带人回家吗？
Every day buy medicine and food for you,
每天给你买药、吃的，
no need to spend money.
不需要花钱。
Besides, next month you have to pay rent again.
而且，下个月你又得交房租了。
Where does the money come from?
钱从哪里来？
if you become a female dancer calmly,
如果你淡定地成为一名女舞者，
and don't go Pai Jiu bet,
也别去赌酒，
Why should it be this way?
为什么会这样呢？
Are you still blaming me?
你还在怪我吗？
Don't underestimate that girl.
别小看那个女孩。
Too much money.
太多钱。
After I succeeded in getting this business,
当我成功获得这个生意后，
we don't need to worry about food and drink,
我们不需要担心食物和饮料，
and care about that little money.
并关心那点钱。
You talked for so long,
你们聊了这么久，
also don't talk about what business
也不谈什么生意
Also don't talk to anyone.
也不要和任何人说话。
What can I expect from you?
我能对你有什么期望？
I told you to throw things in the trash
我告诉过你把东西扔进垃圾桶
have you thrown it away?
你把它扔掉了吗？
I'm very tired today.
我今天很累。
Tomorrow it's thrown again, it's not the same
明天又扔了，不一样了
what if the woman saw it?
如果女人看到了怎么办？
Look, okay?
看看，好吗？
Stupid!
愚蠢的！
You didn't hear what I said.
你没有听到我说的话。
If she didn't come to learn to dance,
如果她不是来学跳舞的
do you know now the CCP and its military power
你现在知道中共及其军事力量吗
is hunting me.
正在追捕我。
He... Where could he be
他……他会在哪里？
I ask you,
我问你，
will he come tomorrow?
他明天会来吗？
We've agreed.
我们已经同意了。
Will come.
将会来。
Tomorrow night,
明天晚上，
kill him.
杀了他。
You're crazy
你疯了
I can't commit murder.
我不能杀人。
So do you still want to come with me?
那么你还想跟我一起去吗？
I can't kill people either.
我也不能杀人。
Take it.
拿去。
Tomorrow night,
明天晚上，
you told him,
你告诉他，
Do you want to eat late at night first?
你想先吃晚饭吗？
Then, look for a quiet street.
然后，寻找一条安静的街道。
While he wasn't paying attention,
趁他不注意的时候，
when he wasn't paying attention.
当他不注意的时候。
Even if no one is looking
即使没人看
Gunshots will also be heard.
还会听到枪声。
Then you
然后你
past the old factory road.
过了老工厂路。
There was no one there.
那里没有人。
Moving on the road.
行驶在路上。
do you know
你知道吗
this thing in my hand
我手里的这个东西
absolutely priceless
绝对无价的
so now we
所以现在我们
must be very careful
必须非常小心
there can be no fault at all
不可能有任何过错
why are you dressed like this?
你为什么穿成这样？
What are you going to do?
你会怎样做？
Just got home this night, still dressed like this.
晚上刚回到家，还是这样的打扮。
Still so fragrant
还是那么香
Why?
为什么？
Allowing you not to come home all night.
让你整夜不回家。
Haven't answered my question yet.
还没回答我的问题。
Good.
好的。
Then I answer honestly.
那我就老实回答吧。
One
一
ballroom dancing
交际舞
happy
快乐的
I forgot the time, so I came home late.
我忘记了时间，所以很晚才回家。
Two
二
dressed like this.
穿成这样。
Certainly
当然
Want to ask me to dance.
想请我跳舞。
Three, what is that?
三、那是什么？
Why is it so fragrant
为什么这么香
delicious or not?
好吃不好吃？
From France?
来自法国？
The aroma is delicious.
香气扑鼻。
But this dance hall
但这间舞厅
you...
你...
Isn't it unsuitable to go?
不是不适合去吗？
Why can't I go?
为什么我不能去？
You feel that my face is not good
你觉得我脸不好看
or my body?
还是我的身体？
But my status is not good.
但我的状态并不好。
You see, you are my wife.
你看，你是我的妻子。
Married
已婚
young woman,
年轻女子，
next time you want to go, you can tell me.
下次你想去的话可以告诉我。
I'll accompany you.
我会陪你。
I suddenly remembered one sentence
我突然想起一句话
I told you, there are people,
我告诉过你，有人，
in the heart
在心里
small braids have not been cut neatly.
小辫子没有剪整齐。
What is meant is you
意思是你
still accompanies me to the dance hall
依然陪我去舞厅
I heard you accompanied that big artist
听说你陪那个大艺术家
didn't come home overnight.
一夜没回家。
Don't be angry yet.
先别生气。
True, or not?
是真是假？
I'm just worried about a friend.
我只是担心一个朋友。
Then you tell me.
那你告诉我。
Who are you going with?
你和谁一起去？
Male or female?
男女不限？
You guess.
你猜。
Look at it.
看它。
Look, aren't you angry?
看看你不生气吗？
You must be taking revenge on me yesterday,
昨天你一定是在报复我吧
han Lu, ya?
han Lu, ya?
I don't care about that at all.
我根本不在乎这个。
I just feel
我只是觉得
even though they are husband and wife?
即使他们是夫妻？
After married
结婚后
must also enjoy absolute freedom.
也必须享有绝对的自由。
No one needs to interfere
不需要任何人干涉
True, or not?
是真是假？
Correct.
正确的。
Wait.
等待。
I haven't asked you yet.
我还没问你呢。
Why was the door lock also replaced?
为什么门锁也换了？
From now on
今后
I sleep on the bed, you sleep on the sofa.
我睡床上，你睡沙发。
Why?
为什么？
Then I sleep on the sofa.
然后我就睡在沙发上。
Don't.
不。
Don't, don't.
不要，不要。
You... sleep in bed. you sleep in bed.
你……睡在床上。你睡在床上。
I sleep on the sofa.
我睡在沙发上。
I want to sleep on the sofa.
我想睡沙发。
Which key is this?
这是哪把钥匙？
This?
这？
Shanghai's nightlife is truly rich.
上海的夜生活真是丰富。
I used to live in vain.
我曾经活得很虚无。
According to you,
照你说的，
What cheongsam should I wear tomorrow?
明天应该穿什么旗袍？
Are you still going tomorrow?
明天还去吗？
Guoguo, you are taking revenge on me.
果果，你这是在报复我。
Deliberately making me angry, huh?
故意惹我生气吧？
Don't blame me for telling the truth.
别怪我说实话。
You're the one wearing this Cheongsam,
穿这件旗袍的就是你
in Shanghai is out of date.
在上海已经过时了。
You wear this outfit to the ballroom
你穿着这套衣服去舞厅
people will count
人们会数数
You're just a country girl selling flowers.
你只是一个卖花的乡下姑娘。
Straight?
直的？
I'll tell you how to spray perfume
我来教你喷香水的方法
sprinkle a drop
洒一滴
That's an angel
那是天使
two drops, that's called sexy.
两滴，这才叫性感。
Like you spilled a bottle all over him,
就像你把瓶子泼到他身上一样
they must think you are a dew flower seller.
他们一定以为你是卖露花的。
And most importantly
最重要的是
in a Shanghai dance hall
在上海的一个歌舞厅里
11 o'clock is the gold field.
11点是金田。
What about the beautiful women?
那些美丽的女人呢？
After dancing on the golden field,
在金色的田野上翩翩起舞后，
they have disbanded.
他们已经解散了。
Like this just came back.
就这样刚回来。
Certainly no one had invited before
当然之前没有人邀请过
too sorry
太抱歉了
chen Jia Ping
chen Jia Ping
I tell you, I was angry
我告诉你，我很生气
If you're angry, you...
如果你生气了，你...
And Han Lu didn't come home overnight.
而韩璐当晚也没有回家。
Irritating.
令人恼火。
Shameless.
不要脸。
Never mind, this fuss
没关系，这大惊小怪
in a long time,
在很长的时间，
can keep your distance
可以保持距离
I hope he's not really mad at me.
我希望他没有真的生我的​​气。
And also,
并且，
Don't take my things carelessly.
别乱拿我的东西。
What's that?
那是什么？
Placed under the mattress.
放在床垫下面。
It's all a thought
这都是一个想法
prevention of the main danger to peaceful government.
预防和平政府面临的主要危险。
Don't look at it carelessly
不要粗心地看它
who wants to see?
谁想看？
I sleep.
我睡觉。
Eavesdropping?
窃听？
He thought I couldn't see.
他以为我看不见。
Good night.
晚安。
Enough already.
已经足够。
This time there was a problem,
这次有问题，
I've been on duty for the past few days...
这几天我一直在值班...
No problem.
没问题。
Did he reconcile or betray?
他是和解还是背叛？
Hey.
嘿。
Yumo Painting and Calligraphy Shop.
玉墨书画店。
Good.
好的。
Old friends,
老朋友，
everyone coming?
大家都来吗？
Two punctures
两次刺破
section chief Chen
陈科长
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Dry grass.
干草。
Why are there still people in the dry grass?
干草丛里怎么还有人？
Yesterday
昨天
Captain Zhao, they arrested a CCP member.
赵队长，他们抓了一个中共党员。
Is dead
死了
he asked me to take it out.
他让我把它拿出来。
It's sad.
这是可悲的。
Two punctures.
两处刺伤。